<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="3.6.2">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://localhost:4000/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2018-02-25T23:26:59+00:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/</id><title type="html">Farming Data</title><subtitle>An agritech startup</subtitle><author><name>Farming Data</name></author><entry><title type="html">Welcome to Jekyll!</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/posts/2018/02/24/testing.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Welcome to Jekyll!" /><published>2018-02-24T22:16:01+00:00</published><updated>2018-02-24T22:16:01+00:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/posts/2018/02/24/testing</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/posts/2018/02/24/testing.html">&lt;p&gt;You’ll find this post in your &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;_posts&lt;/code&gt; directory. Go ahead and edit it and re-build the site to see your changes. You can rebuild the site in many different ways, but the most common way is to run &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;bundle exec jekyll serve&lt;/code&gt;, which launches a web server and auto-regenerates your site when a file is updated.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To add new posts, simply add a file in the &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;_posts&lt;/code&gt; directory that follows the convention &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;YYYY-MM-DD-name-of-post.ext&lt;/code&gt; and includes the necessary front matter. Take a look at the source for this post to get an idea about how it works.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Jacqui</name><email>jacqui@farmingdata.io</email></author><summary type="html">You’ll find this post in your _posts directory. Go ahead and edit it and re-build the site to see your changes. You can rebuild the site in many different ways, but the most common way is to run bundle exec jekyll serve, which launches a web server and auto-regenerates your site when a file is updated. To add new posts, simply add a file in the _posts directory that follows the convention YYYY-MM-DD-name-of-post.ext and includes the necessary front matter. Take a look at the source for this post to get an idea about how it works.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Our new blog series: Why do we do what we do?</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/posts/2018/02/18/why.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Our new blog series: Why do we do what we do?" /><published>2018-02-18T22:16:01+00:00</published><updated>2018-02-18T22:16:01+00:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/posts/2018/02/18/why</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/posts/2018/02/18/why.html">&lt;h3 id=&quot;have-we-ever-told-you-why-we-do-what-we-do&quot;&gt;Have we ever told you why we do what we do?&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s been more than 2 months since we’ve started at the &lt;a href=&quot;https://seriousimpact.co.uk/&quot;&gt;Allia Serious Impact&lt;/a&gt; incubator, and we’ve had an overall exciting, rewarding experience. In the coming weeks, I’ll be sharing with our followers what we’ve been up to so far! But before I do that, let me share with you the reasons why we’re set on doing what we’re doing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;h2 id=&quot;to-improve-market-access-and-enhance-fairness-in-the-supply-chain-for-smallholder-farmers-and-buyers&quot;&gt;“To improve market access and enhance fairness in the supply chain for smallholder farmers and buyers.”&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h5 id=&quot;thats-our-mission&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;That’s our mission.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/h5&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Brought together by our passion to reduce poverty and hunger, my co-founders David, Paul, and I are developing an integrated digital platform that provides all of the marketplace tools in one place.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Unlike countries like the UK, where about 1% of the population work in farming, over 60% of the population in sub-Saharan African countries work in agriculture. Many are smallholder farmers, who produce about 80% of the domestic food supply. Agriculture is also a primary source of household income for smallholders - for example, in Tanzania, about 56% of a smallholder family’s income comes from farming. That’s an incredibly large percentage of their annual household income, which can average less than US$ 1,005 or between US$ 1,006 and US$ 3,995 for low-income and lower-middle countries, respectively.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Given the majority of the population in low- and lower-middle income countries in smallholder agriculture, we believe there’s a huge opportunity in agriculture to generate a big social good impact.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As Bill Gates said:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;h2 id=&quot;helping-the-poorest-smallholder-farmers-grow-more-crops-and-get-them-to-market-is-the-worlds-single-most-powerful-lever-for-reducing-hunger-and-poverty&quot;&gt;“Helping the poorest smallholder farmers grow more crops and get them to market is the world’s single most powerful lever for reducing hunger and poverty.”&lt;/h2&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;-Bill Gates, World Food Prize speech, 15 October 2009.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;well-why-use-digital-tech-now-you-might-ask&quot;&gt;Well, why use digital tech now, you might ask?&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Countries across the continent of Africa are leapfrogging over old communication technologies. With the proliferation of mobile phones, sub-Saharan Africa is the fastest growing mobile market in the world!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Because of these growing opportunities, we believe now is the time! For innovative solutions like ours to develop useful technologies that contribute to reducing poverty and hunger.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;need-for-user-centricity&quot;&gt;Need for user-centricity&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But simply developing the technology will not solve the issue. We strongly recognise the need for a user-centric approach. Without input and feedback from stakeholders, any technology that’s being developed might not even be effective at the end! Which is why we’ll be actively reaching out and engaging with them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This blog is part of a series that I hope will demonstrate to you the specific mission of our startup, the developments as we progress, and other findings along our journey. Next, I’ll share with you what we’ve been up to so far, so stay tuned!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;If you have any questions or want to connect with us, feel free to contact us through email (info@farmingdata.io) or Twitter (&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/farming_data&quot;&gt;@farming_data&lt;/a&gt;)!&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Jacqui</name><email>jacqui@farmingdata.io</email></author><summary type="html">Have we ever told you why we do what we do? It’s been more than 2 months since we’ve started at the Allia Serious Impact incubator, and we’ve had an overall exciting, rewarding experience. In the coming weeks, I’ll be sharing with our followers what we’ve been up to so far! But before I do that, let me share with you the reasons why we’re set on doing what we’re doing. “To improve market access and enhance fairness in the supply chain for smallholder farmers and buyers.” That’s our mission. Brought together by our passion to reduce poverty and hunger, my co-founders David, Paul, and I are developing an integrated digital platform that provides all of the marketplace tools in one place. Unlike countries like the UK, where about 1% of the population work in farming, over 60% of the population in sub-Saharan African countries work in agriculture. Many are smallholder farmers, who produce about 80% of the domestic food supply. Agriculture is also a primary source of household income for smallholders - for example, in Tanzania, about 56% of a smallholder family’s income comes from farming. That’s an incredibly large percentage of their annual household income, which can average less than US$ 1,005 or between US$ 1,006 and US$ 3,995 for low-income and lower-middle countries, respectively. Given the majority of the population in low- and lower-middle income countries in smallholder agriculture, we believe there’s a huge opportunity in agriculture to generate a big social good impact. As Bill Gates said: “Helping the poorest smallholder farmers grow more crops and get them to market is the world’s single most powerful lever for reducing hunger and poverty.” -Bill Gates, World Food Prize speech, 15 October 2009. Well, why use digital tech now, you might ask? Countries across the continent of Africa are leapfrogging over old communication technologies. With the proliferation of mobile phones, sub-Saharan Africa is the fastest growing mobile market in the world! Because of these growing opportunities, we believe now is the time! For innovative solutions like ours to develop useful technologies that contribute to reducing poverty and hunger. Need for user-centricity But simply developing the technology will not solve the issue. We strongly recognise the need for a user-centric approach. Without input and feedback from stakeholders, any technology that’s being developed might not even be effective at the end! Which is why we’ll be actively reaching out and engaging with them. This blog is part of a series that I hope will demonstrate to you the specific mission of our startup, the developments as we progress, and other findings along our journey. Next, I’ll share with you what we’ve been up to so far, so stay tuned! If you have any questions or want to connect with us, feel free to contact us through email (info@farmingdata.io) or Twitter (@farming_data)!</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Who are smallholder farmers? And why is market access an issue?</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/posts/2017/03/17/come-learn-about-us.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Who are smallholder farmers? And why is market access an issue?" /><published>2017-03-17T16:16:01+00:00</published><updated>2017-03-17T16:16:01+00:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/posts/2017/03/17/come-learn-about-us</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/posts/2017/03/17/come-learn-about-us.html">&lt;h3 id=&quot;so-what-exactly-is-our-idea&quot;&gt;So, what exactly &lt;em&gt;is&lt;/em&gt; our idea?&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&quot;what-is-our-startup-doing-specifically&quot;&gt;What is our startup doing specifically?&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the following video, Jacqui will tell what Farming Data is all about. So, check it out and come learn about us!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;text-center&quot;&gt;
&lt;iframe src=&quot;https://player.vimeo.com/video/206495368&quot; width=&quot;720&quot; height=&quot;405&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; webkitallowfullscreen=&quot;&quot; mozallowfullscreen=&quot;&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;</content><author><name>Jacqui</name><email>jacqui@farmingdata.io</email></author><summary type="html">So, what exactly is our idea? What is our startup doing specifically? In the following video, Jacqui will tell what Farming Data is all about. So, check it out and come learn about us!</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Interview by Cambridge TV</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/posts/2016/10/13/cambridge-tv.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Interview by Cambridge TV" /><published>2016-10-13T16:16:01+00:00</published><updated>2016-10-13T16:16:01+00:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/posts/2016/10/13/cambridge-tv</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/posts/2016/10/13/cambridge-tv.html">&lt;p&gt;Our co-founder Paul was interviewed by Luther Phillips, as part of the Cambridge Entrepreneurs series on Cambridge TV. Check out the video below, or visit the &lt;a href=&quot;https://insight.jbs.cam.ac.uk/2016/cambridge-tv-cambridge-entrepreneurs-farming-data/&quot;&gt;Judge Business School’s webpage&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;text-center&quot;&gt;
&lt;iframe src=&quot;https://player.vimeo.com/video/187169977&quot; width=&quot;720&quot; height=&quot;405&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; webkitallowfullscreen=&quot;&quot; mozallowfullscreen=&quot;&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;em&gt;If you have any questions or want to connect with us, feel free to contact us through email (info@farmingdata.io) or Twitter (&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/farming_data&quot;&gt;@farming_data&lt;/a&gt;)!&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Paul</name><email>paul@farmingdata.io</email></author><summary type="html">Our co-founder Paul was interviewed by Luther Phillips, as part of the Cambridge Entrepreneurs series on Cambridge TV. Check out the video below, or visit the Judge Business School’s webpage. If you have any questions or want to connect with us, feel free to contact us through email (info@farmingdata.io) or Twitter (@farming_data)!</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Hello!</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/posts/2016/04/25/hello.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Hello!" /><published>2016-04-25T16:16:01+00:00</published><updated>2016-04-25T16:16:01+00:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/posts/2016/04/25/hello</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/posts/2016/04/25/hello.html">&lt;h3 id=&quot;welcome-to-our-new-website&quot;&gt;Welcome to our new website.&lt;/h3&gt;</content><author><name>Farming Data</name><email>info@farmingdata.io</email></author><summary type="html">Welcome to our new website.</summary></entry></feed>